Bad news, Brother!
Ed, do you know him?
That means...
Where do you think
you're going, Ed?
I know your every move.
S-Sensei... What are you doing here?
Sensei?
You mean her?
She's our alchemy teacher.
Where's Al?!
Y-Yes, ma'am!
Oh, I beg your pardon.
Thanks for leading us here, when you must be so busy.
Do you know where Al is as well?
Um, you see...
I'm Alphonse...
Ah, is that so? My, my...
Were you trying to escape by disguising yourself?!
Stories about you two reach me quite often, my moronic pupils!
Like how you broke away from my teachings
and lowered yourselves to
become dogs of the military!
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
The formal orders for your transfer have come through.
Starting next week,
you'll be serving in Central, huh?
Yes.
We're going to miss you here. You've been quite colorful.
Not at all.
Not as much as when you
were younger, General. Check.
It's now or never, General.
And here with all of your work, I was able to take it easy.
You have my deepest sympathy.
Checkmate.
I've lost after all, eh?
Your one victory is my parting gift.
I accept it most gratefully.
General...
While you're giving away parting gifts,
I have some subordinates whom
I would like to take with me to Central.
Mm-hmm, sure.
Take them.
I thank you.
Are you two all right?
We never expected that Sensei
would come for us, huh, Brother?
Ow...
Damn...
She even took away
my silver watch.
I guess we're going
straight to Dublith.
Still, I'm surprised.
I expected your teacher to be someone rougher, not a pretty lady like her.
What are you talking about?
You've met her before, you know.
It was in Resembool that
Sensei took us on as her pupils.
In Resembool?
Remember, when we had all that heavy rain?
ECW, 26%; ICW, 34%;
lipids, 19%; proteins... um...
Wouldn't it be quicker if we just went with the elements composing a human body?
Say, what have you been
studying so hard about lately?
It's a secret!
It doesn't have anything to do with you, Winry!
You sneaks! You're always
keeping secrets between you two!
See you!
We're having stew
for supper tonight!
Okay! We'll see you later!
Yay!
Whoever invented stew is great!
It's got milk in it,
but it's still so delicious!
What are you going on about?
The idea of sticking milk into
vegetable soup was awesome!
Scientists need to change over to that kind of thinking.
There are limits to what we can do
studying alone, Brother.
We can't make it on
our knowledge alone.
Mm-hmm.
I wonder what we're missing for human transmutation.
Why is human transmutation forbidden in the first place?
Isn't it because it's a dangerous transmutation that no one has succeeded at?
Remember, they say that a whole country was destroyed in one night...
The story of the Philosopher's Stone in the eastern desert, right?
Right, right. It tells of them
trying to create a complete human,
but the whole population got dragged into it.
That's just a fairy tale.
His formulas...
If we can make sense of this...
But...
It's written there that human transmutation is forbidden.
I've made up my mind, Al.
We're going to bring
Mom back to life.
I sure hope the river
doesn't give way.
Hold it, you two!
We're going to go help!
This is bad. Hey!
Bring more sandbags here!
Hey, what are you doing?! It's dangerous there!
All right!
I did it!
The transmutation circle!
Brother!
H-Hey!
This is dangerous,
so please keep back.
That's what I should
be saying to you!
Get out of there, quickly!
Whoa...
No way!
She didn't even use
a transmutation circle!
That huge amount of mass, all at once...
That should hold it for a while.
Unbelievable. Who are you?
Just a couple passing through.
Where's the nearest hospital?!
A doctor! Get a doctor!
Hey, stay with us!
You really saved us.
Resembool is in your debt.
Please, let us through.
Pardon us.
Um, Auntie?
Who are you calling your auntie?!
W-We're sorry...
P-Please, take us on as pupils,
Miss.
Pupils?
We're able to use a little alchemy.
We want to become
better at it, so please!
No way.
Why not?!
I don't take on pupils.
We have a store, so we have to be getting back to Dublith.
Take us with you! Take us as pupils!
Ah! How pesky!
If you do learn alchemy,
what do you two want to do with it?!
Uh...
We...
We want to be helpful to others!
What about your parents' permission?
Well, about that...
Those two don't have any parents.
I'm the one who
looks after them now.
I just don't know
how to handle this.
One month...
Can I take them for
provisional training?
To see if it's really worth teaching them alchemy.
Please allow me to ascertain
the talents that these children have.
And if they don't have any talent?
I'll send them right back here.
And if we pass our
provisional training?
Then we'll proceed to
full-fledged training.
We won't be coming back in a month!
I knew you'd say that.
Training! Training!
I'm sure there must be
a huge laboratory there!
And maybe we can
read lots of books!
Sure we can!
It's training, after all!
That's right!
Sensei, you performed an incredible transmutation back there
without even a transmutation circle, huh?
Sensei, by any chance,
are you a State Alchemist?
Don't you lump me in with those dogs of the military,
who can calmly take
people's lives if ordered to!
I see.
That person from back then...
I'm loose.
All right!
Let's make a break for it, Al!
Brother!
Looks like you still haven't learned your lesson, huh?
Check.
W-Wait!
I can't wait.
Aw, man!
What's up with that?
I heard it's a style of chess from the eastern island countries.
Yes? Yes, he's here.
That sure was fun
the other night, huh?
So, about this weekend...
It's okay, it's okay...
Ah, hello. I'm a little busy right now...
That's got it fixed.
Thank you so much.
Yes?
I'm asking you,
by all means,
please include me too!
When you were in the Investigations Department,
you served under Hughes, right?
Come in.
Master Sergeant Kain Fuery,
Second Lieutenant Heymans Breda,
Second Lieutenant Jean Havoc,
First Lieutenant Riza Hawkeye,
Warrant Officer Vato Falman—
it has been decided that these five will transfer with me to Central.
I will accept no objections.
Come with me!
We didn't get away after all, huh?
Nope...
I get chills just thinking about what's going to happen now.
Sensei!
Menny! How is Chico doing?
They say she's about
to have her babies.
Is that right?
That'll liven things up, huh?
Izumi-san!
Welcome back!
Mason-san!
Huh? Edward-kun,
it's been too long!
You've really grown a lot!
This is what pisses me off...
Huh? Who is this in the armor?
Er, his younger brother, Alphonse.
You've really grown a lot...
Huh? Aren't you eating?
N-No...
Just eat it.
Okay.
Al-kun, you eat too.
It's delicious.
I'm already full.
You've had quite a brutal journey,
haven't you?
You shouldn't be doing such dangerous things.
But it hasn't been all terrible.
We've also helped people.
That's right, we helped deliver a baby.
Silly, you call that helping?
All we did is get all flustered.
That's true.
But then, the family helps out as the mother risks her life,
and everyone is blessed when a person is born.
That's right.
That's the way you guys
received life, too.
Take pride in the life you have.
Now that you mention it,
Izumi-san, do you have any children?
Hey there, you know, this...
Alchemy! You must've gotten better, right?
Show me something!
Sure, as much as you want. Al...
I'll come too.
Izumi...
Is that so? They watched a life being born, huh?
Those children had themselves a nice experience.
Okay, here goes.
You've gotten good, haven't you?
I'm next.
Sensei, welcome home!
Welcome home!
Sensei, my train is broken.
Fix it.
The axle broke, huh?
Let me have that.
Fix it with alchemy!
Nuh-uh. Don't rely on
alchemy for everything.
Fix whatever you can fix
by yourself on your own.
There, all done.
Ew, that's ugly.
Well, excuse me.
If you don't want it
fixed so ungracefully,
be more careful with it
so it doesn't break.
Sensei, thanks!
I'll be back when I break it again!
Don't break it, I said...
Sensei! Sensei!
What's the matter, Menny?
Chico... It's Chico!
Chico's up there!
I'm going up!
Nice catch!
Chico...
Sensei, is Chico broken?
Mm-mm, no. She died.
Sensei, fix Chico!
Izumi-sensei, you can make anything, right?
So, as far as Chico goes...
I can't do that.
A life is different
from a thing, you see,
and I am not God.
Chico's life has ended,
and she isn't coming back.
But...
But... up until just a while ago...
I cannot create a life for Chico,
but I can make a grave for her.
When something is alive,
that life will expire at some point.
The body will return to the earth,
where flowers will bloom on top of it.
Their spirit will serve to nourish other people's feelings
and continue to live on
inside their hearts.
Everything in the world
flows around and circulates.
People's lives are like that as well.
Even though I know
as much about it as I do,
it's still so hard to make
a child understand death.
Sensei,
have you ever wanted to
bring someone back to life?
That's the second time
you've asked that question.
I was only wondering, that's all.
Ouch...
What does that have
to do with anything?!
The basis of the transmutation circle
is the power of the circle.
The circle demonstrates the circulation of power,
and through the act of drawing it,
the invoking of that power becomes possible.
By knowing the laws and flow of power, you can contend with all things.
Those who would create things after accepting and understanding this—
they are alchemists.
The world constantly follows the motion of a great current.
The death of people
is part of that flow,
and as such, you must not think about bringing them back to life.
Al, that armor is empty on the inside, isn't it?
Ed's arm and leg are
Automail as well, right?
H-How did you...
The weight from when I threw you...
your left footsteps sounding
different from your right ones...
Did you think I wouldn't notice?
You fools!
Sensei...
Earlier, you did not use
a transmutation circle, did you?
You wouldn't have happened to have seen it, have you?
I have.
What happened?
Tell me everything.
Sensei,
I...
We...
transmuted... our mom.
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 28: "One Is All, All Is One"
We are so very small.
However, we have everything in the world within us.